Guide to the Volga (Saratov, Russia): Editorial Files, 1966 - 2000
Department of Special Collections
Volga (Saratov, Russia): editorial files,
1966 - 2000
M1316
10 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Volga was a literary magazine published in Saratov, Russia, between the late 1960's and 2000. While it survived under the Soviet era and into the post-Communist Russian era, it was nevertheless shut down by Russian authorities in 2000.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions on access.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 2001. Accession no. 2001-348
Historical Note
Volga was a literary magazine published in Saratov, Russia, between the late 1960's and 2000. While it survived under the Soviet era and into the post-Communist Russian era, it was nevertheless shut down by Russian authorities in 2000.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
The collection includes correspondence between the editors and the authors, galleys, manuscripts, author information cards, photographs, and official registration documents for the operation of the journal filed with first the Soviet and then subsequently the Russian government.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Russian literature--20th century--History and criticism.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - Poetry Department - correspondence [1 of 2]1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Poetry Department - correspondence [2 of 2]1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Poetry Department - Correspondence between M. Chernyshov and beginner authors [1 of 3]1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Poetry Department - Correspondence between M. Chernyshov and beginner authors [2 of 3]1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence between V.Medvedev and editors about translation "Slovo o polku Igoreve"1980-82 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Poems by different authors and reviews on them [1 of 2]1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Poems by different authors and reviews on them [2of 2]1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence between M.Chernyshov and bigenner authors1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Poetry department - correspondence, poems of beginner authors1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Poetry department - correspondence with authors1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Prose department - correspondence with authors [1 of 2]1986-89 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Prose department - correspondence with authors [2 of 2]1986-89 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Poetry department - correspondence between editors and beginner authors1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Poetry department - correspondence with authors1979, 85, 87 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Poems by beginner poets [1 of 2]1984-1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Poems by beginner poets [2 of 2]1984-1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Poetry division: correspondence1984-1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Reviews, correspondence1984-1999 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Records of outgoing correspondence1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Records of incoming correspondence1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Records of outgoing correspondence1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence between beginner authors and editors1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Reviews by M.Chernyshov on poems of beginer authors [1 of 3] (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Reviews by M.Chernyshov on poems of beginer authors [2 of 3] (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Reviews by M.Chernyshov on poems of beginer authors [3 of 3] (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Series 2. Editorial files
  - Correspondence between F.Krjukov and A.Serafimovich (1912-1917) Introductory article by V.M.Proskurin, Proskurin's letters to "Volga"1988, 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - A.Chemonin, "Budut sudit' potomki":corrected versions1988, 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - S.Borovikov: Na perevale - corrected version1988, 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Articles by V.Khodasevich, A.Sheshin, T.Nikolaeva1988, 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - P.Egorov: Perebor - typeprint1988, 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Issue #9 [1 of 2]1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Issue #9 [2 of 2]1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Letters of B.Pasternak to K.Fedin, R.Likht: I tvorchestvo i chudotvorstvo... (about B.Pasternak)1983, 89 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - V.Kazakov: Pravo na chest'; reviews1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - A.Pasternak: Sceny iz zhizni Ivana Ogurtsova, dissidenta i terrorista [1 of 3]1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - A.Pasternak: Sceny iz zhizni Ivana Ogurtsova, dissidenta i terrorista [2 of 3]1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - A.Pasternak: Sceny iz zhizni Ivana Ogurtsova, dissidenta i terrorista [3 of 3]1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - V.Molodjakova: Iz pervoi knigi Ivana Bunina; T.Goricheva: Vzyskanie pogibshikh; A.Amusin: Ya sluzhil Rodine, a ne pravitelstvu; V.Berdinskikh: Ocherki krestjanskoi tsivilizatsii v Rossii1990 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - L.Shestov: O pererozhdenii ubezhdenij u Dostoevskogo; B.Boruhov: Pohvala ponimaniju ili ochen' slozhnyj Mandel'shtam; book reviews1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - B.Sirotin: poems; V.Volodin: A potom byla nichja; E.Rein: poems; N.Klimontovich: Tsvety dalnikh mest; V.Salimov: poems; M.Zenkevich: Muzhitsky sfinks1990 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - A.Slapovsky: Iskrennyi khudozhnik; Dummies by: V.Prozorov, A.Mol'ko, L.Slanevsky, E.Silkina1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - O.Plebeisky: poems; G.Fedotov: Svjatye drevnei Rusi; E.Govor: Vospominanija ob Arteme Vesjolom; V.Jakovlev: Iz 4-go kruga; V.Makarov: Shakhmatov v Gubarevke.1990, #2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - A.Solzhenitsyn: Arkhipelag Gulag; poems of different authors; E.Popov: short stories; V.Nabokov: Korol', dama, valet...1990, #2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - V.Makarov: Shakhmatov v Gubarevke; reviews; poems by different authors1990, #3 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - reviews by different authors; A.Solzhenitsyn: Atkhipelag "Gulag"1990, #3 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - A.Solzhenitsyn: Atkhipelag "Gulag"; E.Popov: Ljubitel' knig A.Djuma; E.Rein: poems1990, #3 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - E.Popov: stories; poems by different authors; G.Fedotov: Svjatye drevnei Rusi1990, #3 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - V.Nabokov: Korol', dama, valet...1990, #3 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Shnitke: Iz 4-go kruga, A.Shnitke govorit; Shakhmatov v Gubarovke; E.Govor: Vospominanija o A.Veselom1990, #3 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Poems by different authors; E.Popov: stories; V.Nabokov: Korol', dama, valet...1990, #3 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - G.Fedotov: Svjatye drevnei Rusi; A.Shnitke: Iz 4-go kruga; L.Borisevich: Vospominanija ob A.Vesjolom1990, #3 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - G.Fedotov: O Pushkine; O.Sedakova: Pamjati Leni Gubanova; V.Shavyrin: Zhizn' beskonechnaya; book reviews; G.Blinov: Ekho jazycheskikh vremjon1990, #6 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Volzhsky arkhiv: Sinen'kie; old dummies of issue #6; poems by B.Slutsky; E.Rasumov and unknown authors1990, #6 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - A.Cherchesov: Dozhd' - odinoky prokhozhij; A.Egorov: poems; I.Show; Lusi Crown1990, #6 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Cover page of issue #6; E.Krjukova: poems, Y.Krasavin: Oni nastupajut; F.Sukhov: Solovki; S.Bardin: Gaika rez'bovaja.1990, #6 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Typeprints by: A.Velichansky, L.Karimova and other authors (poems); Article about N.Shatrov1990, #6 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - A.Egorov: poems; book reviews; I.Show: Lusi Crown; Kibal'nik: article about Pushkin1990, #6 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Book reviews; Volzhsky arkhiv; V.Sudarikov: Sinen'kie.1990, #6 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - E.Krjukova, F.Sukhov - poems; K.Popov: Zapiski o Saratove1990, #6 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - O.Sedakova: Pamjati Leni Gubanova; L.Gubanov: poems; Volzhsky arkhiv.1990, #6 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - G.Blinov: Ekho yazycheskikh vremjon; V.Shavyrin: Zhizn' beskonechnaya; G.Rusakov: Oklik (poems)1990, #6 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Y.Krasavin: Oni nastupajut1990, #6 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - A.Cherchesov: Dozhd' - odinokij prokhozhij1990, #6 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - E.Chepurnykh: poems; M.Bazankov: Mazurkin; D.Prigov: Revoljutsia; poems by: S.Kekova, G.Gorina1990, #10 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - L.Yakovlev: Romantichesky nash imperator1990, #10 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - N.Valentinov-Volsky: Vstrechi s Leninym1990, #10 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - G.Shengeli: poems; V.Bareiko: gostepriimstvo travy velikoi; Y.Chuikov: Khlebnikovy v Kazani1990, #10 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - R.Moudi: Zhizn' posle zhizni1990, #10 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Articles by: S.Borovikov; N.Tjapugina, A.Safronova1990, #10 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - A.Dargomoschenko: Kontext=konspekt; Volzhskij arkhiv; short info about authors; book reviews1990, #10 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - O.Sedakova: Pamjati A.Tarkovskogo; "Sredi knig i zhurnalov"; V.Bochkov: Katerina li ona?1990, #12 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Typeprints by: G.Adamovich, Y.Nikitin, V.Larsky, A.Vasilenko, I.Aristov1990, #12 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - S.King: Domashny address - turjma; N.Valentinov: Vstrechi s Leninym; poems of different authors1990, #12 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - V.Aleinokov: poems, Z.Dakenov: Poletim, kukushechka, v dal'nie kraja; V.Popov: poems1990, #12 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - L.Darell: Justin - typeprint [1 of 2]1993, #5 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - L.Darell: Justin - typeprint [2 of 2]1993, #5 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - L.Darell: Justin - dummie (translated by V.Mikhailin)1993, #5 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - G.Ostrovsky: Avtoportret rossiiskogo 'tret'ego soslovia"; B.Prushkov: Zapiski ob uzhenii ryby pod Saratovom1993, #5 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - O.Kushlina: Russkie poetessy serebrjanogo veka; G.Gachev: ekologicheskaya ispoved'; E.Popov: Bard - po-russki- pesnopevets; S.Stranovsky: religioznye motivy v russkoi sovremennoi poezii; reviews1993, #5 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - A.Drugas: poems; E.Vodonos: Letters of Y.Oksman to R.Reznik; V.Zernov: Zapiski russkogo intelligenta; E.Dobrenko: Grammatika boja - jazyk batarei1993, #11 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - V.Volodin: Pasha Zalepukin - drug angelov1993, #11 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - I.Yuganov: Telegi i gnomy; Y.Buida: rasskazy; book reviews1993, #11 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - A.Cherchesov: Rekviem po zhivuschemu (novel)1994, #3 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Dummies: V.Vakhrushev, A.Purin, A.Slapovsky1994, #3 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Dummies: L.Kraval', D.Chernyshevsky; book reviews; Volzhsky arkhiv1994, #3 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - V.Zernov: Zapiski russkogo intelligenta; V.Linetsky: Paraboks Narbikovoi; V.Berezhkov, D.Strotsev: poems1994, #3-4 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - I.Pomerantsev: Al'by i serenady1994, #3 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - N.Balashov: Dostoevsky i russkij perevod Biblii; Antonova: 100-letie dnja rozhdenia Dostoevskogo v Saratove; Barsht: O portretnykh risunkakh Dostoevskogo1996, #5-6 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - L.Saraskina: Zhertvoprinoshenie1996, #5-6 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Typeprints: A.Kozlov, E.Pozdnin, Y.Nikitin1996, #5-6 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Typeprints: S.Terekhin, E.Vodonos, L.Grekolova1996, #5-6 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Typeprints: V.Djakonov ("Pevchie"), V.Melnik ("E.Tolstaya v zhizni avtora "Oblomova")1996, #5-6 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - A.Romanov: Vremja sobirat' kamni [1 of 3]1996, #5-6 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - A.Romanov: Vremja sobirat' kamni [2 of 3]1996, #5-6 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - A.Romanov: Vremja sobirat' kamni [3 of 3]1996, #5-6 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - A.Ozhiganov: Apologia PostmodernistovaMistika Rainera Marii Ril'ke - sent to A.Gaponenkov1996,2000 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - A.Andruschenko: Prikhoperskie zori (poems 1941-1997)1997 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - D.Gai: Detstvo Ivana [1 of 2]1997 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - D.Gai: Detstvo Ivana [2 of 2]1997 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - V.Zakharov: Novoe issledovanie po istorii Saratova; poems by: A.Kasimov, A.Ozhiganov, Y.Dronov1998, #5-6 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - About authors; I.Slavin: Minutnoe - perezhitoe; Reviews by: A.Kolobrodov; A.Genatulin: Pepelische1998, #5-6 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - poems by: I.Shul'gin, S.Schurin; Sh.Abdullaev: Nepodvizhnaja mestnost'; A.Kolobrodov: Kak nashi bratja; A.Slapovsky: Kino, kotorogo net1998, #7 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Reviews by: B.Glubokov, E.Arbitman, A.Kolobrodov, V.Chernjaev; I.Pyrkov: Dom Ablomova; A.Titov:Sobaka lajala1998, #7 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Nedvizhimost' 6/98, 1/98, 9/98, 30/98T.Frank: Pamjati serdtsaV.Pugachev: Podvigi zhizni A.Oksman; Pushkin i dekabristy + comments (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - S.Sinel'nikov: Akhtyrskoi Bozhiei Materi Guselsky zhensky monastyr'1998 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - I.Slavin: Minuvshee - perezhitoe (vospominanija)1998 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - S.Borovikov: E.Popov kak natsional'ny pisatel'; A.Titov: rasskazy1998 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - N.Yanev, E.Zaugarov: poems; reviews by: O.Rogov, V.Seleznev, M.Yampolsky1998 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Sredi knig i zhurnalov: book reviews; A.Aleksandrov: poems; V.Smirnov: Rytsar' krasoty1998 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - E.Fedorenko - typeprints (poems)1998 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Editing schedule; kalendar info from Saratov public library1986-92 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Unsigned dummies (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Reviews: O.Fomicheva, M.Nagovitsyn, S.Sinel'nikov; A.Sedov: Politichesky anekdot (fragment knigi); N.Ivenshev: Chee; E.Sapritsky: poems; D.Zernov: poems; R.Doroshenko: Luchshy prozaik Ekpevari1999 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - A.Genatullin: Vbrod (typeprint)1999 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - D.Zarubin: Tremadot (radioroman)1999 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Typeprints by: A.Maslova, E.Cherkasov, G.Stepanchenko1999 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Zapiska ob organizatsii literaturnogo kruzhka1999 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Typeprints by: M.Sokolov, E.Chepkasov, V.Seleznev, Y.Rudakov1999 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Typeprints by: V.Shapko, I.Lebedeva1999 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - P.Protopopov: Smutnoe vrenja glazami svjaschennika (1913-1920)Introductory article by S.Sinel'nikov2000, #1 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Issue #4132000 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Issue #4132000 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - O.Khafisov: Kizh [1 of 3] - typeprint (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - O.Khafisov: Kizh [2 of 3] - typeprint (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - O.Khafisov: Kizh [3 of 3] - typeprint (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - D.Zarubin: Derevenskaya ljubov'; Chekist po klichke "Avtor"; Imprinting (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - V.Shapko: Dyrjaven'kij Kinematograf (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - J.Le Karre: Malen'kaya barabanschitsa [1 of 3] (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - J.Le Karre: Malen'kaya barabanschitsa [2 of 3] (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - J.Le Karre: Malen'kaya barabanschitsa [3 of 3] (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - A.Gorbatenko: Anabazis i amfitrion; book of poems (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Series 3. Reviews
  - Different reviews1983 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Different reviews1986-91 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Different reviews [1 of 3]1987-88 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Different reviews [2 of 3]1987-88 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Different reviews [3 of 3]1987-88 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Reviews (poetry) [1 of 2]1987-88 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Reviews (poetry) [2 of 2]1987-88 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Reviews1988-89 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Reviews1988-89 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Reviews1990, #3 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Reviews1990, #6 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Reviews1993, #5, 11 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Reviews1994, #3, 4 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Reviews1998, #7 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Reviews1998 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Series 4. Photographs
  - Photo [1 of 6]1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Photo [2 of 6]1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Photo [3 of 6]1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Photo [4 of 6]1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Photo [5 of 6]1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Photo [6 of 6]1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Photo 1967-68, 70, 73-75, 86 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Photo [1 of 7]1973-75 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Photo [2 of 7]1973-75 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Photo [3 of 7]1973-75 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Photo [4 of 7]1973-75 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Photo [5 of 7]1973-75 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Photo [6 of 7]1973-75 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Photo [7 of 7]1973-75 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Photo [1 of 4]1966-67 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Photo [2 of 4]1966-67 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Photo [3 of 4]1966-67 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Photo [4 of 4]1966-67 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Photo [1 of 9]1968-75 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Photo [2 of 9]1968-75 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Photo [3 of 9]1968-75 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Photo [4 of 9]1968-75 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Photo [5 of 9]1968-75 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Photo [6 of 9]1968-75 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Photo [7 of 9]1968-75 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Photo [8 of 9]1968-75 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Photo [9 of 9]1968-75 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Photos, facsimiles, grammophone recod, miscellaneous1965, 67, 78, 79 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Photo [1 of 3]1988, #2 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Photo [2 of 3]1988, #2 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Photo [3 of 3]1988, #2 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Photos to: Tol'ko odna chelovecheskaya zhizn by K.Fedin [1 of 2] (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Photos to: Tol'ko odna chelovecheskaya zhizn by K.Fedin [2 of 2] (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Photo; pictures of some authors 1991, #7 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Photo 1967, 1973-75; Illustrations; R.Dal': Promezhutochnaya verbal'nost' (typeprint); A.Slapovsky - project of the book cover page (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Series 5. Registration documents
  - Registration documents - related materials1991 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Orders, Agreements, Payrolls, editing schedule1992-94 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Payrolls, related documents1995-96, 99 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Blank forms (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Copy of "Ustav", related doc's1990, 97 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Trade-union statements1968-69 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Series 6. Author information
  - Author's info cards [1 of 4] (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Author's info cards [2 of 4] (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Author's info cards [3 of 4] (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Author's info cards [4 of 4] (Box 22, Folder 11)